

# **MANEESH NAND**

student

**About Me** 

Driven by an insatiable curiosity and a thirst for knowledge, I am an accomplished engineering student intrested to make a meaningful impact in art design, web development, and technological innovation. With a diverse skill set that encompasses Angular, React, DevOps, Android development, and the creation of immersive experiences through augmented and virtual reality using Blender, I bring a unique blend of creativity and technical expertise to every project I undertake.

### **Professional Experience**

 Working on college team project: SPORTS VIDEO SUMMARIZATION

DEC'22 - Present

=>It's a machine learning based project which uses 3D resnet, CNN,Knapsack that combines the most important key frames in the match based on the user desired duration of the summary.

Worked as an intern at TCPL company

During my internship at TCPL as a web developer, I had a fantastic learning experience. I had the opportunity to delve into backend development using Angular, expanding my skills in web development. Additionally, I gained exposure to the basics of Android development, thanks to the guidance and support of my colleagues.

JUNE'22 - JULY'22

- Projects that I dedicated my efforts to:
  - 1. Action horror game using Blender & Unreal Engine.
  - 2.3D cube rendering in 2D plane using Python, matrices.
  - 3. Object Detection with Image AI in Python.
  - 4.WEB chat server using HTML & CSS.
  - 5. Shopping mall safety and maintenance using ARDUINO.

AND MANY OTHER MINOR PROJECTS FOR THE RESPECTIVE COURSES THOUGHT 2020 - 2022

### **Additional mentions**

#### Engaging in part-time freelance work 2022 - present as a video editor.

Design team Lead for shunya CLub(PESU) 2022 - present

2021 - 2022Part of Design team in IEEE society.

2022 - present Hold the role of class representative.

#### **Achievements**

Secured 6th prize in a hackthon Hacknight'2021 conducted by Hack night(PESU).

**IBMZ** datathon selected into 10 teams for developing Al based rain water preservation using

geolocation.

## **My Contact**

- maneeshnand14@gmail.com
- +91 8328143014
- PES UNIVERSITY, Electronic city, Bangalore
- www.thecreativefreak.com

#### **Hard skills**

- · Programming languages (e.g., Python,C, C++,Java)
- · Data mining and analysis
- Fimiliar with DevOps tools
- Blender & Unreal Engine proficiency
- · Competative programming
- Graphic & Web Design
- Drawing & Photography
- Editing&Videography

#### Soft skills

- Creativity
- · Presentation skills
- Decision making
- Communication
- · Multi-tasking

#### **Education Background**

 PES UNIVERSITY, Bangalore Bachelor of Technology COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEER 2020 - Present

 Narayana Junior college Prepared for JEE mains and ADVANCE 2018 - 2020

 Viswabharati english medium School Gudivada, Andhra pradesh

2012 - 2018